

Munich, Germany

■ kirillbobyrev@gmail.com | ★ kirillbobyrev.com | 🖸 kirillbobyrev | 🛅 kirillbobyrev | 💆 @kirillbobyrev

Summary_

I am Software Engineer at Google and work on clangd, C++ Language Server implementation that brings IDE experience to Visual Studio Code, Vim and other editors. I contribute to **LLVM** very often (**list** of commits). I specialize in Compilers and Machine Learning. C++, Rust and Python are typically my languages of choice.

Work Experience

Google

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Nov 2019 - Present

- Significantly improved clangd, Clang-based C++ Language Server Protocol implementation that brings IDE-like experience for for Visual Studio Code, Vim, CLion, XCode, Eclipse, a number of other IDEs and text editors.
- · Designed and implemented IncludeCleaner: IWYU-like functionality in clangd for warning users about unused and missing headers.
- Implemented Remote Index service for LLVM and Chrome. This allows developers with slow machines to get precise code completion and navigation for these large projects. Deployed the service to Google Cloud and maintained it, the service is handling 1.5M+ requests per week.
- · Took responsibilities of Product Manager and UX Researcher: continuously interviewed our users and processed feedback, built feature roadmaps and prioritized tasks based on the needs of our users.

Handl, Y Combinator-backed Machine Learning startup

DATA SCIENTIST Feb 2019 - Jun 2019

- · Secured a contract with AMG Mercedes Benz, worked out how to translate their business goals into fine-grained technical problems and led
- Built Deep Learning models for a our clients' variety of tasks such as Image and Sound Segmentation, Image and Video Classification.
- Contributed to state-of-the-art Deep Learning models for Optical Character Recognition in PyTorch and TensorFlow.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Designed and implemented Dex efficient index for code completion based on Russ Cox design of Google Code Search.
- · Replaced previous index implementation and gained 15x-60x performance boost while providing more features such as advanced filtering for code completion-based symbol search.
- Reduced code completion average latency from 16 μs to 1.09 μs for LLVM codebase (3M Lines Of Code) and from 119 μs to 1.9 μs for Chromium codebase (16M LOC).
- Implemented Variable length Byte (VByte) compression algorithm and reduced memory overhead by 60% with insignificant loss of speed and no precision loss.
- · Identified performance bottlenecks in commonly used LLVM YAML serializer and made it 3 times faster.

Google

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

- Elevated performance of Clang-Rename, Clang-based tool that can perform efficient renaming actions in large-scale projects such as renaming classes, functions, variables, arguments, namespaces etc.
- Fixed inconsistent renaming bugs, added support for template classes, introduced new functionality and gained users for Clang-Rename.
- Built Vim and Emacs plugins for Clang-Rename tool.
- Designed and prototyped Clang-Refactor, which later transformed into Clang's Refactoring Engine
- Started a discussion about building Language Server Protocol implementation which later resulted in clangd creation and became the main focus of the team.
- Added new checks to **Clang-Tidy** and reduced false-positive rate for existing ones.

Google

GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE STUDENT

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Implemented Code Clone Detection tool in Clang Static Analyzer and used it to detect over 400 similar code pieces in Git, Vim, OpenSSL and other projects. The **overview** of key results is hosted on GitHub.

Talks & Publications

LLVM Developers' Meeting conference lightning talk

San Jose, CA, USA

"DEX: EFFICIENT SYMBOL INDEX FOR CLANGD" (VIDEO RECORDING AND SLIDES)

2018

Education

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology (MIPT)

B.S. IN MATHEMATICS AND PHYSICS

Open Source

LLVM

CONTRIBUTOR 2015 - Present

Participating in LLVM-related projects and working on Clang-based C++ tooling. This includes contributing to clangd, Clang-Tidy, Clang Static Analyzer and other C++ Language tools. My work has been featured multiple times on **LLVM Weekly** covering the most important recent changes. **List** of all my commits.

Skills_

Programming Languages C++, Rust, Python, Haskell

Expertise Compilers, Machine Learning: Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Computer Vision, Self-Driving Vehicles

Frameworks Jax, NumPy, Tensorflow, Pytorch, LLVM